export interface generalKnowledgeProps {
  question: string;
  answers: string[];
  correct: string;
}

export const generalKnowledge: generalKnowledgeProps[] = [
  {
    question: "In which country did the ancient Olympic Games originate?",
    answers: ["Greece", "Rome", "Egypt", "China"],
    correct: "Greece",
  },
  {
    question: "Who is considered the father of the modern Olympic Games?",
    answers: [
      "Michael Phelps",
      "Jesse Owens",
      "Pierre de Coubertin",
      "Usain Bolt",
    ],
    correct: "Pierre de Coubertin",
  },
  {
    question: "What do the five rings on the Olympic flag represent?",
    answers: [
      "The five continents",
      "The five Olympic sports",
      "The five founding countries of the Olympic Games",
      "The five Olympic values",
    ],
    correct: "The five continents",
  },
  {
    question: "Which country has hosted the most Summer Olympic Games?",
    answers: ["Greece", "United Kingdom", "France", "United States"],
    correct: "United States",
  },
  {
    question: "Which of the following is NOT an Olympic sport?",
    answers: ["Basketball", "Cricket", "Gymnastics", "Swimming"],
    correct: "Cricket",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The Olympic motto is 'Citius, Altius, Fortius'. What does it mean in English?",
    answers: [
      "Faster, Higher, Stronger",
      "Better, Bigger, Best",
      "More, Less, Equal",
      "Old, New, Future",
    ],
    correct: "Faster, Higher, Stronger",
  },
  {
    question: "In which year were the first modern Olympic Games held?",
    answers: ["1948", "1924", "1896", "1960"],
    correct: "1896",
  },
  {
    question: "Which country won the most medals at the 2020 Tokyo Olympics?",
    answers: ["China", "United States", "Japan", "Great Britain"],
    correct: "United States",
  },
  {
    question: "Who is the most decorated Olympian of all time?",
    answers: [
      "Simone Biles",
      "Usain Bolt",
      "Serena Williams",
      "Michael Phelps",
    ],
    correct: "Michael Phelps",
  },
  {
    question: "Which city hosted the 2016 Summer Olympics?",
    answers: ["Rio de Janeiro", "London", "Beijing", "Tokyo"],
    correct: "Rio de Janeiro",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What is the name of the Olympic mascot for the Paris 2024 Olympics?",
    answers: ["Miraitowa", "Oli", "Phryges", "Nagano"],
    correct: "Phryges",
  },
  {
    question: "What does the saffron colour on the Indian Flag represent?",
    answers: [
      "Courage and strength",
      "Truth and purity",
      "Peace and tranquillity",
      "Prosperity and growth",
    ],
    correct: "Courage and strength",
  },
  {
    question: "In the centre of the white band, what emblem is depicted?",
    answers: [
      "A lion",
      "A lotus flower",
      "The Ashoka Chakra",
      "A map of India",
    ],
    correct: "The Ashoka Chakra",
  },
  {
    question: "What do the 24 spokes of the Ashoka Chakra signify?",
    answers: [
      "The 24 states of India",
      "The 24 principles of righteousness",
      "The 24 hours of a day",
      "The 24 seasons in a year",
    ],
    correct: "The 24 principles of righteousness",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What is the ratio of the length to the width of the Indian National Flag?",
    answers: ["1:1", "2:1", "4:3", "3:2"],
    correct: "3:2",
  },
  {
    question: "On which day was the Indian National Flag officially adopted?",
    answers: [
      "22nd July 1947",
      "26th January 1950",
      "1st November 1947",
      "30th June 1947",
    ],
    correct: "26th January 1950",
  },
  {
    question: "Who designed the Indian National Flag that we know today?",
    answers: [
      "Mahatma Gandhi",
      "Jawaharlal Nehru",
      "Pingali Venkayya",
      "Sarojini Naidu",
    ],
    correct: "Pingali Venkayya",
  },
  {
    question: "As per the Flag Code of India, who can hoist the National Flag?",
    answers: [
      "Only government institutions",
      "Only on national holidays",
      "Any Indian citizen at any time",
      "A member of the public, a private organization, or an educational institution",
    ],
    correct:
      "A member of the public, a private organization, or an educational institution",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What is the significance of the green colour at the bottom of the Indian Flag?",
    answers: [
      "Strength and courage",
      "Fertility, growth, and auspiciousness",
      "Peace and harmony",
      "Knowledge and learning",
    ],
    correct: "Fertility, growth, and auspiciousness",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which peak holds the title of the highest mountain entirely within Indian territory?",
    answers: ["Kangchenjunga", "Nanda Devi", "K2", "Saltoro Kangri"],
    correct: "Nanda Devi",
  },
  {
    question: "Which mountain range is known as the 'Sahyadri' in Maharashtra?",
    answers: [
      "Eastern Ghats",
      "Satpura Range",
      "Aravalli Range",
      "Western Ghats",
    ],
    correct: "Western Ghats",
  },
  {
    question: "What is the elevation of Kanchenjunga?",
    answers: ["7,000 metres", "8,586 metres", "9,518 metres", "10,212 metres"],
    correct: "8,586 metres",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which mountain range is home to India's highest peaks, including Nanda Devi and Kamet?",
    answers: [
      "Karakoram",
      "Kumaun Himalayas",
      "Eastern Ghats",
      "Western Ghats",
    ],
    correct: "Kumaun Himalayas",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The Siachen Glacier, the world's highest battlefield, is located near which peak?",
    answers: ["Nanga Parbat", "Sia Kangri peak", "Gasherbrum I", "Shilla"],
    correct: "Sia Kangri peak",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Mount Everest, the highest peak in the world, is part of which mountain range that borders India?",
    answers: ["Karakoram", "Himalayas", "Hindu Kush", "Pamir Mountains"],
    correct: "Himalayas",
  },
  {
    question: "The Bogibeel Bridge will connect which two places in Assam?",
    answers: [
      "Dibrugarh and Dhemaji",
      "Dibrugarh and Sadiya",
      "Dibrugarh and Tinsukia",
      "Dibrugarh and Jorhat",
    ],
    correct: "Dibrugarh and Dhemaji",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The Pamban Bridge, a cantilever bridge, connects which two places?",
    answers: [
      "Chennai and Mamallapuram",
      "Mumbai and Elephanta Island",
      "Rameswaram and mainland India",
      "Kanyakumari and Thiruvananthapuram",
    ],
    correct: "Rameswaram and mainland India",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Why are airplane windows designed to be round or oval instead of square?",
    answers: [
      "To provide a better view for passengers",
      "To reduce the weight of the aircraft",
      "To enhance cabin pressure regulation",
      "To minimize stress concentration and prevent structural failures",
    ],
    correct: "To minimize stress concentration and prevent structural failures",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which company popularized hackathons by holding them regularly since the 2000s?",
    answers: ["Google", "Facebook", "Apple", "Microsoft"],
    correct: "Facebook",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Who were the key individuals involved in the creation of Facebook's Like button?",
    answers: [
      "Mark Zuckerberg and Sheryl Sandberg",
      "Justin Rosenstein and Leah Pearlman",
      "Chris Hughes and Dustin Moskovitz",
      "Eduardo Saverin and Andrew McCollum",
    ],
    correct: "Justin Rosenstein and Leah Pearlman",
  },
  {
    question: "Who is known as the 'Father of the Indian Constitution'?",
    answers: [
      "Mahatma Gandhi",
      "Jawaharlal Nehru",
      "Dr. B.R. Ambedkar",
      "Sardar Patel",
    ],
    correct: "Dr. B.R. Ambedkar",
  },
  {
    question: "What is the Preamble of the Indian Constitution?",
    answers: [
      "A detailed outline of the fundamental rights guaranteed to Indian citizens",
      "A brief introductory statement that sets out the guiding purpose and principles of the Constitution",
      "A brief introductory statement that outlines the document's guiding principles and purpose.",
      "A comprehensive list of the duties and obligations of Indian citizens",
    ],
    correct:
      "A brief introductory statement that sets out the guiding purpose and principles of the Constitution",
  },
  {
    question: "Which Indian state is known as the 'Land of Five Rivers'?",
    answers: ["Punjab", "Haryana", "Uttar Pradesh", "Bihar"],
    correct: "Punjab",
  },
  {
    question: "Which Indian state is known as the 'Land of the Rising Sun'?",
    answers: ["Arunachal Pradesh", "Meghalaya", "Mizoram", "Nagaland"],
    correct: "Arunachal Pradesh",
  },
  {
    question: "The Preamble of the Indian Constitution starts with the phrase:",
    answers: [
      "We, the People of India...",
      "In the name of God...",
      "India, a Sovereign Socialist Secular Democratic Republic...",
      "To secure to all its citizens...",
    ],
    correct: "We, the People of India...",
  },
];
